<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<docs>
	<members name="tokenServices">
		<TokenServices>
			<summary>
				Provides services for token generation, validation, and management in authentication workflows.
			</summary>
		</TokenServices>

		<RefreshTokenAsync>
			<summary>
				Refreshes a token by validating the provided refresh token and generating a new access token.
			</summary>
			<param name="request">The request containing the access token and refresh token.</param>
			<param name="cancellationToken">A token to monitor for cancellation requests.</param>
			<returns>
				A <see cref="AuthResponse"/>representing the new authentication response or <see cref="Error"/>an error
			</returns>
		</RefreshTokenAsync>

		<GenerateToken>
			<summary>
				Generates a new JWT access token for a given user with their roles and permissions.
			</summary>
			<param name="user">The application user for whom the token is generated.</param>
			<param name="roles">A list of roles assigned to the user.</param>
			<param name="permissions">A list of permissions assigned to the user.</param>
			<returns>
				A tuple containing the generated token string and its expiration time.
			</returns>
		</GenerateToken>

		<GenerateRefreshToken>
			<summary>
				Generates a secure refresh token and its expiration time.
			</summary>
			<returns>
				A tuple containing the generated refresh token string and its expiration date.
			</returns>
		</GenerateRefreshToken>

		<ValidateToken>
			<summary>
				Validates a given JWT token and extracts the user's ID if valid.
			</summary>
			<param name="token">The JWT token to validate.</param>
			<returns>
				The user ID if the token is valid; otherwise, <c>null</c>.
			</returns>
		</ValidateToken>

		<GenerateResponse>
			<summary>
				Generates an authentication response for a given user, including an access token, refresh token, and expiration details.
			</summary>
			<param name="user">The application user for whom the response is generated.</param>
			<returns>
				An <see cref="AuthResponse"/> containing token details and user information.
			</returns>
		</GenerateResponse>
	</members>
</docs>

